panelbase.net 2016-04-15

# panelbase.net - Privacy Statement

Last updated: 8th Oct 2015

At panelbase.net we are committed to protecting your privacy. Panelbase.net is operated by [Dipsticks Research Ltd](http://www.dipsticksresearch.com/), a professional market research agency who are also members of the [Market Research Society's Company Partner Scheme](http://www.mrs.org.uk/companypartner/companies.htm). Our primary business is to conduct research studies in order to provide insights for our clients, whilst ensuring that the personal identity of those participating in our surveys is protected. Results from surveys and research discussions are not linked to the individual identity of respondents without the informed consent of those respondents.

By using this site, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. 

Personally identifiable information (PII) is only collected with your full knowledge and permission. In those circumstances where we retain personal information, it is used only for the administration of your panelbase.net account and by trusted personnel only. Your personal data is stored in secure systems and is never sold or otherwise transferred to any third party unless explicitly stated in the survey briefing. If your PII is being shared, we will inform you of exactly what information will be passed to third parties and the reason for doing so.

We reserve the right to retain data pertaining to; partial registrations, deactivated or unsubscribed member accounts and all associated website and survey activity for the purpose of protecting panelbase.net and to prevent potentially fraudulent activity. All such storage of data will adhere to the Data Protection Act 1998 and all other prevailing UK law at all times.

Our web servers recognise your Internet Service Provider and/or referrer's domain name, IP address and the identity of your Internet browser. This non-personal information helps panelbase.net to determine the total number of visitors to its website and to individual pages within the website. We also engage IP address-based technologies to assist in the prevention of fraudulent activity on the panelbase.net website and within our web-based surveys. These technologies are developed and operated by panelbase.net and its employees **only** and never involve 3rd parties.

panelbase.net conducts research surveys using a variety of different technologies and methods of communication. The following points constitute the guiding principles by which we conduct our business:

  * As an active member of panelbase.net you will receive survey invitations via the preferred methods of contact that you have chosen when registering. Usually this will be via email but may also include SMS (delivered to your registered mobile phone), telephone, or by post.
  * Active members of panelbase.net will also receive periodic email communications such as: newsletters, administrative notifications, login reminders, happy birthday emails, and prompts to update your panelbase.net account where this has not been done for a period of 3 months or more. All of these communications will come from panelbase.net's secure mail servers. You will never receive communications from 3rd parties as a result of being an active member of panelbase.net.
  * All of the information collected in our surveys will only be used for research purposes.
  * We will **never** sell or otherwise transmit anyone's name or other personal information to a mailing list.
  * For all research purposes, only aggregate data are used or data where all personally identifiable or sensitive information have been removed.
  * We take all steps to protect the security and integrity of the information that respondents/participants provide.
  * Respondents/participants have the right to check the data that have been collected and to correct inaccurate personal information.
  * Registered members of panelbase.net can deactivate their account at any time using either of the following mechanisms. All requests to be unsubscribed are processed automatically and will trigger a confirmation email being sent to the panelbase.net member's registered email address.
    1. Using the unsubscribe link contained within the footer of all emails sent to the panelbase.net member's registered email address.
    2. Using the appropriate link from the 'Help' page within the panelbase.net member's account.
    3. By following the instructions on the [unsubscribe](https://www.panelbase.net/login/unsubscribe.aspx) page.

panelbase.net is committed to protecting the security of its members' personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect information from unauthorised access, use, or disclosure, both online and offline. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer servers with limited access that are located in access-controlled facilities. Additionally, when we transmit sensitive personal information over the Internet, such as your e-mail address, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol with Extended Validation (EV SSL).

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. 

The table below explains the cookies we use and why. 

Origin | Name | Purpose | More Information  
---|---|---|---  
Panelbase.Net  |  ASPNET_SessionId  
cookie.ASPXAUTH  |  The ASPNET_SessionId cookie is essential for any users accessing our site to access forms. This includes login forms and registrations etc. This cookie is removed when you close your browser. 

The cookie.ASPXAUTH is used to signify you are logged in to our website. Without this cookie users are unable to remain logged in to our website. This cookie is removed when you close your browser. 

|   
Google Analytics  |  __utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmv  
__utmz  |  These cookies are used by Google Analytics to store information, such as what time the current visit occurred, whether the visitor has been to the site before, and what site referred the visitor to the web page.  |  [ More about Google privacy ](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html "Read about Google privacy")  
  
We may occasionally update this privacy statement without notice.

panelbase.net welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you believe that panelbase.net has not adhered to this privacy statement, please contact us by e-mail or postal mail (details below), and we will make every reasonable effort to promptly determine and remedy the problem.

panelbase.net  
The Mill  
Hexham Business Park  
Burn Lane  
Hexham  
Northumberland  
NE46 3RU 

Email: [support@panelbase.net](mailto:support@panelbase.net?subject=Privacy%20statement%20enquiry)  
Tel: 0800 1958492 

© 2005 - 2016 panelbase.net. All rights reserved. panelbase.net is a division of Dipsticks Research Ltd.
